Guide to the Joan Holt Papers on the Indian Point Energy Center TAM.754
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Joan Holt Papers on the Indian Point Energy Center
1978-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Holt, Joan
TAM.754
11 linear feet in 11 record cartons
Joan Holt was the Director of the Indian Point Project at the New York Public Interest Research Group in the late 1970s and early 1980s. She also was involved in activism concerning disarmanent, civil rights, women's rights, and United States involvement in the Vietnam War. The Joan Holt Papers (dated 1978-1989) consists of materials created and collected by Holt documenting her involvement in efforts to decommission the Indian Point Energy Center (IPEC). Materials in this collection include petitions, correspondence, memoranda, flyers and other ephemera, press releases, newspaper clippings and reports produced by the New York Public Interest Research Group concerning safety investigations, nuclear power plants' impact on the health of local citizens, emergency preparedness protocols, and the prospect of nuclear accidents like Three Mile Island and Chernobyl. This collection also includes transcripts of testimonies by Holt and other experts at local public meetings and federal hearings with the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission. A significant portion of this collection consists of the working documentation used to prepare for these meetings, including notes, surveys, memoranda of talking points, and reports. This collection provides evidence of the organizing efforts that occur as part of a nuclear decommissioning campaign, as well as the broader antinuclear movement in the 1970s and 1980s.
Scope and Contents
The Joan Holt Papers (dated 1978-1989) consists of materials created and collected by Holt documenting her involvement in efforts to decommission the Indian Point Energy Center (IPEC). Materials in this collection include petitions, correspondence, memoranda, flyers and other ephemera, press releases, newspaper clippings and reports produced by the New York Public Interest Research Group concerning safety investigations, nuclear power plants' impact on the health of local citizens, emergency preparedness protocols, and the prospect of nuclear accidents like Three Mile Island and Chernobyl. This collection also includes transcripts of testimonies by Holt and other experts at local public meetings and federal hearings with the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission. A significant portion of this collection consists of the working documentation used to prepare for these meetings, including notes, surveys, memoranda of talking points, and reports. This collection provides evidence of the organizing efforts that occur as part of a nuclear decommissioning campaign, as well as the broader antinuclear movement in the 1970s and 1980s.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical Note
Joan Holt was the Director of the Indian Point Project at the New York Public Interest Research Group in the late 1970s and early 1980s. She earned her B.A. in Psychology from Queens College (1959) and her M.A. in Psychology from New York University (1975). She also was involved in activism concerning disarmanent, civil rights, women's rights, and United States involvement in the Vietnam War.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Joan Holt in August 2018; the accession number associated with this gift is 2018.122.
Nuclear power plants -- New York (State); Antinuclear movement.; Nuclear power plants -- Health aspects; Nuclear power plants -- Safety measures; Nuclear power plants -- Decommissioning; Emergency management -- New York (State); Holt, Joan; U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission; Indian Point Nuclear Power Plant (N.Y.)
- Transcripts, Correspondence, NYPIRG Reports, 1979-1983 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, Meeting Notes, Petitions, Surveys and Questionnaires, 1979-1986 (Box 2)
- Press Releases, Newspaper Clippings, 1979-1988 (Box 3)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1979-1982 (Box 4)
- Press Releases, Correspondence, Research Files, Testimony Transcripts, 1980-1987 (Box 5)
- Testimony Transcripts, Financial Records, 1981-1983 (Box 6)
- Reports, Testimony and Hearing Transcripts, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
- Reports, Testimony and Hearing Transcripts, 1982-1983 (Box 8)
- Testimony Transcripts, Public Statement to New York State Assembly Special Committee on Nuclear Plant Safety, 1980-1986 (Box 9)
- Newspaper Clippings, Testimony and Hearing Transcripts, 1978-1989 (Box 10)
- Newspaper Clippings, Report, Publications on Antinuclear Movement, 1979-1983 (Box 11)